Omar Al-Midani

+963 938625359 # omarmidani90@gmail.com

Summary

Junior Full Stack Developer. Experienced with Laravel Framework and React JS library. Well-versed in numerous programming languages including HTML5, PHP, JavaScript, TypeScript, CSS, MySQL, C++, Java, as well as strong problem-solving skills with over 1400 problem solved.

Highlights

- Complex problem solver
- Excellent teaching skills
- Strong decision maker
- Work under pressure
- Hard Worker.

- Mathematical aptitude
- Organized
- Excellent English Speaker
- Team Work
- Team Leader

Experience

1. Back-end Developer for University Project. 11/2023 to 1/2024

- Cooperate with front-end developers to create a university project using Laravel as back-end and flutter as a front-end.
- Carry out quality assurance tests to discover errors and optimize usability.

2. Front-end React JS and Back-end Laravel. 4/2024 to (now)

- Working on a web application for the **Syrian Red Crescent** as the only Front-end developer and part of the Back-end team.
- The application basically organize Red Crescent's Warehouses, show them Transactions between each warehouse and doners, give them the ability for following the transactions state, with mobile application that give the doners and keepers the ability to see their Transactions, as well as Reports for any period of time that the admin want to see, with many and many other features that simplify their work.
- Will be published soon.

3. Front-end React JS Developer (Freelance Project). 7/2024 to (now)

- Working on a web application for **Furniture Warehouse** as Front-end developer and cooperate with Back-end Laravel developer.
- The major goal of the website is to organize the selling operation, know for each customer what are the furniture that he bought with how much he paid and so on. In addition, it gives the admin the ability to show the goods on the website as well as to know the

expenses of the warehouse such as the worker expenses or the warehouse expenses and so on.

- Will be published soon.

4. Game Discovery website with Mosh Hamadani course. 3/2024 to 6/2024

- attended two parts of Mosh Hamadani course (React 18 for Beginners and React 18 Advanced topics) and done with him a full website that is game discovery website.
- deploy it on Vercel and ready to use. (check the Links section)

5. Participating in ACM contests in Syria:

- Passed the local contest in Damascus university and got 9th rank with a bronze medal.
- Participated Three times.
- Have an account on problem solving websites such as Codeforces with rating reaches to be specialties. (check the Links section)
- Coach teaching problem solving Algorithms.
- 6. Worked on an OpenGL project for the university with C++.
- 7. Simulation for a Submarine Movement with Three JS and pure JS for physics. (University Project).
- 8. Good experience with GitHub and Bitbucket.

Highlights for ReactJS

- State management with Zustand library.
- React Query to link between the Back-end and React-app.
- Learned for Styling bootstrap and Chakra UI library.
- Animation.
- Responsive layout.
- Real-time notifications.
- Build with TypeScript or JavaScript.

Highlights for Laravel

- Experience with MySQL.
- RESTful APIs.
- Real-time notifications.
- Editing pages within Blade System .
- Working with MVC.
- Making custom traits, Requests, Resources and services.
- · Working with Repositories.

Additional

- Good dealing with deploying ReactJS apps.
- Hosting Laravel projects.

Education

IT Engineer (Fourth Year). (10/2021 to present)

Certifications

Competitive Programming: Bronze Medal At Damascus University Contest (ACM Contest). (6/2023)

Languages: Diploma in English at NewHorizons Center. (Jul/2021)

Links

GitHub: https://github.com/Omarmidanii

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/omar-al-midani/

Codeforces: https://codeforces.com/profile/Omar Al Midani

Game Discovery App: https://game-discovery-app-xi.vercel.app/